jamieoliver.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Jamie Oliver

## About this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy explains what personal information we hold about you, how we collect it, and how we use and may share information about you. It relates to any personal information we collect from you via:

  * our Websites: jamieoliver.com, jamiesministryoffood.com and any other Jamie Oliver website that links to this Privacy Policy 
  * our Social Pages: social media pages and accounts for “Jamie Oliver” and “Jamie’s Ministry of Food UK”
  * our **Services** : our subscription services and any other Jamie Oliver services that link to this Privacy Policy.

It also relates to any personal information you provide or submit to us by email, phone, SMS, on social media (for example in response to a competition or promotion), in Messenger and other chat bots, in letters and in person.

This Privacy Policy should be read together with our: 

There may be other privacy policies or terms and conditions that apply to certain services we provide or promotions/competitions we run. Please always read these when you participate in these promotions or register for these services. 

**This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Jamie Oliver restaurants or cookery school’s websites or social media pages.**

## Who we are

When you visit our Websites, use our Services, or interact with us via our Social Pages or otherwise submit information to us, Jamie Oliver Limited (‘ **us** ’ and ‘ **we** ’) is a ‘data controller’ and gathers and uses certain information about you. When we do so we are regulated under the General Data Protection Regulation which applies across the European Union (and will still apply to the United Kingdom even after Brexit) and local applicable laws.  
Other companies might sell Jamie Oliver-branded products or provide Jamie Oliver related services under licence. Please make sure you always check the privacy policy of the websites you use so you know who runs the website and how they will use your personal information.

## Information we collect about you

The types of information we collect about you depends on how you interact with us. There are three ways in which we may collect your personal information:

  1. directly from you;
  2. from other sources; and
  3. automatically.

The table set out under the section 'More about the information we collect and hold' at the bottom of this policy sets out in detail the information we collect and hold about you by each of these methods. For a summary of each method, click below.

## Information we receive directly from you

Whenever you interact with us directly, we receive information from you, for example when you:

  * contact us, for example by using the contact forms on our Websites, by using Facebook Messenger, or by e-mailing us
  * sign-up for an account with jamieoliver.com
  * sign up to receive any of our marketing or newsletters
  * subscribe to one of our Services (for example, “Five Day Veggie Challenge” or "Jamie's Jan-Plan")
  * enter any competitions or prize draws we run
  * comment on recipes and content on the Websites
  * submit content to us, for example if you post a selfie and use one of our hashtags on your public social media account in response to one of our competitions (please also read our [Terms for Contributions](https://www.jamieoliver.com/terms/#terms-and-conditions))

## Information received from other sources

Sometimes we also obtain information about you from other sources, for example when you:

  * use any of our Services or Website Functions which enable you to sign-in via a third party service, for example if you log-in to your jamieoliver.com account with Facebook - we receive some of your account information
  * use the Jamie Oliver e-commerce website to purchase any products - if you allow us to, we receive information from the website operator about which products you purchase 
  * complete one of our surveys – we receive your answers and any personal information you provide within your answers from Survey Monkey
  * apply to be an audience member or participate in one of our TV programmes

For more details about the types of information we receive from these and other sources, including where it is held and where it came from, see the table under the section 'More about the information we collect and hold' at the bottom of this policy.

## Information we collect automatically

When you access and browse any of our Websites or use our Services, we collect information about your usage and activity on our Websites or Services using certain technologies, such as cookies and web beacons.

Depending on the cookie settings in your browser and the cookie preferences you set when you first access our Websites or Services, our third-party service providers, advertisers, and/or partners may also place view, edit, or set their own cookies. If you would like to find out more about cookies, including how we use them and what choices are available to you, please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.jamieoliver.com/cookies/).

## How we use your personal information

We explain the ways in which we plan to use your personal information and the legal basis on which we rely for each use in the table below and in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.jamieoliver.com/cookies/).  

Generally, the reasons we use your personal information can be categorised as follows:

  * to personalise our Services to you
  * to enable you to partake in our prize draws or competitions 
  * to maintain and improve our Services and our Websites’ infrastructure
  * to sell advertising space on the Websites – this allows us to provide certain sections of our Websites (and our delicious recipes!) to you for free
  * if you have opted-in to this, or where otherwise allowed by law, to market our products and services to you

Where we propose to use your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first (and if required, obtain your consent).

## Who we share your personal information with

### _With other Jamie Oliver Companies_

We routinely share infrastructure, resources and technology with our affiliated companies Jamie Oliver Productions Ltd, Jamie’s Italian International Limited, Recipease Limited and Jamie Oliver Licensing Ltd (‘ **Jamie Oliver Companies** ’). This means any personal information we hold about you may be shared with these companies. This helps us provide you with a relevant, and consistent experience across all Jamie Oliver platforms. All Jamie Oliver Companies are located in the United Kingdom.  Sometimes, as noted in the table under the section 'More about the information we collect and hold' below, we may also share your personal information with Jamie’s Italian Limited. For example, if we receive an inquiry from you about a Jamie Oliver restaurant we may pass it on to Jamie’s Italian Limited and you may be contacted by one of their employees directly. Jamie’s Italian Limited is located in the United Kingdom.

### _With Third-Party Partners_

We work with suppliers and other companies who help us provide and improve our Websites and Services. Sometimes, these third parties may need to have access to your personal information to provide us with services or to provide services on our behalf. In the table under the section 'More about the information we collect and hold' at the bottom of this policy and the paragraphs below we name (or where this is not possible, names the categories) third parties with whom the information we collect and hold about you may be shared. 

  * **Advertisers**

We work with third-party advertising companies (currently Proper Media LLC, located in the USA) to serve ads while you are visiting our Websites. If you opt-in to our Advertising Cookies, we permit these companies to place and access their own cookies on your computer in the course of serving advertisements on our Websites. The information these companies may obtain through their cookies does not include your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number. Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.jamieoliver.com/cookies/) for further information about Advertising Cookies.

  * **Partners offering Jamie Oliver-branded products and services**

When you buy a product from the [Jamie Oliver Shop](https://shop.jamieoliver.com/), the operator of that website (The Hut.com Limited) will receive the information you share with them to complete the transaction, including shipping and contact details. The Hut.com Limited is located in the UK and its privacy policy is available [here](https://shop.jamieoliver.com/privacy.list).

If you contact us with an inquiry relating to any Jamie Oliver branded products, we may pass on your inquiry to one of our licensees (i.e. the company responsible for producing and selling the relevant product to you) and they may respond directly to you. Our current licensees are based in the EEA and Brazil.

Other companies might sell Jamie Oliver-branded products or provide Jamie Oliver related services under licence. Please make sure you always check the privacy policy of the websites you use so you know who runs the website and how they will use your personal information.

  * **Vendors and service providers**

We provide information and content to vendors and service providers who support our business, such as by providing technical infrastructure services, assisting us to send our marketing and newsletters to customers who have consented to receive same, analysing how our Websites and services are used, providing customer service, facilitating payments, conducting surveys, or providing fraud detection service.

We may also need to share personal information with other parties, such as external contractors and our professional advisers and potential purchasers of some or all of our business or on a re-structuring. Usually, information will be anonymised but this may not always be possible. We contractually bind all third parties with whom we share personal information to keep your information confidential and to use it only for the purpose of providing their services and pursuant to the applicable privacy legislation in the EU. We may also be required to share some personal information as required to comply with the law. Some of these third-party recipients may be based outside the European Economic Area — for further information including on how we safeguard your personal data when this occurs, see the section about ‘Transfer of your information out of the EEA’ below. 

## Whether information has to be provided by you, and if so why

We’ve outlined in the table below, why each category of personal information we collect from you is required from us to be able to perform the purpose to which it relates and the possible consequences of failing to provide such information. We seek to ensure that our information collection and processing is always proportionate. We will inform you at the point of collecting information from you, whether you are required to provide the information to us or not. We will notify you of any changes to information we collect from you or to the purposes for which we collect and process it.

## How long your personal information will be kept

### _Jamieoliver.com account holders_

When you cancel your jamieoliver.com account we delete all your personal information but we keep a record of the fact that your account was deleted for a reasonable period of time. If you have not logged-in to your account for a long time, we will send you an email to let you know that your account has been set to a ‘dormant’ status and that it will be deleted if you do not take action within one month on the email date. Please note we may retain information from deleted accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our [Terms of Use ](https://www.jamieoliver.com/terms/)and take other actions permitted by law. 

### _Other personal information_

We will keep your personal information while you have an account with us or we are providing any Services to you (including any marketing or newsletter services). Thereafter, we will keep your personal information for as long as is necessary: 

  * to respond to any questions, complaints or claims made by you or on your behalf
  * to show that we treated you fairly
  * to keep records required by law.

We will not retain your personal information for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this policy and when it is no longer necessary to retain your personal information, we will delete or anonymise it. Different retention periods apply for different types of personal information. If you require further details, please see below ‘How to contact us’. 

## Reasons we can collect and use your personal information

This section addresses the legal basis for processing your personal data. Some processing is addressed in multiple sections in the Table set out below because more than one legal basis may apply depending on the circumstances or service and to make it easy for you.  
The legal bases on which we rely in each instance where we collect and use your personal data, generally, are:

  * to fulfil and enforce our [Terms of Use](https://www.jamieoliver.com/terms/), [Terms for Contributions](https://www.jamieoliver.com/terms/) and any other contract we have with you
  * consistent with your consent, which, for newsletters and marketing you may revoke at any time in the Subscription Centre, which can be accessed by clicking the ‘Unsubscribe’ option at the bottom of our emails or by clicking 'Change contact preferences' in your profile (if you have a jamieoliver.com account) - if you're having any issues unsubscribing please email unsubscribe@jamieoliver.com
  * as necessary for our (or others’) legitimate interests, including our interests in providing safe Website/Services, fraud detection, tailoring your experience on our Websites/Services, knowing how customers use our Website/Services and products, keeping our Websites/Services updated and relevant, developing our business and informing our marketing strategy, but only if these are not overridden by your interests, rights or freedoms.

## Transfer of your information out of the EEA

To deliver the Websites and our Services to you, it is sometimes necessary for us to share your personal information outside the European Economic Area (EEA), eg:

  * with your and our service providers located outside the EEA
  * if you are based outside the EEA

These transfers are subject to special rules under European and UK data protection law. Prior to permitting such transfers, we carry out assessments to ensure all personal information transferred will be kept secure. Our standard practice is to use standard data protection model contract clauses that have been approved by the European Commission (as permitted under Article 46(2) of the General Data Protection Regulation) or to only transfer your data to companies that are registered with the Privacy Shield (for transfers to the USA). If you would like further information please see ‘How to contact us’ below. 

## Your rights

Under the General Data Protection Regulation you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, you have the right to access your personal data and require that we rectify any errors in the data that we hold, or request that we erase your personal data subject to certain limitations. In some circumstances, you can also require that we restrict the way we process your personal data, object to its processing or request a copy of your personal data for the purposes of transmitting elsewhere. Where we have requested and obtained your consent to process particular information, you may withdraw that consent at any time. However if we do not hold all the data we need to administer contracts, orders, competitions or challenges you entered into, we may not be able to provide you with these benefits any longer.

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the [Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals rights under the General Data Protection Regulation](http://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/).

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please send your request to us via [this form](https://www.jamieoliver.com/contact/) (select 'Data Protection') or write to us at “Data Protection Officer, Benwell House, 15-21 Benwell Road, London, England” and:

  * let us have enough information to identify you (eg your full name and contact details - including your email address); and
  * let us know what right you want to exercise and the information to which your request relates (eg details of the specific information you require and any relevant dates).

Please note that we may ask you to provide proof of identity when considering your request.  
If your request relates to unsubscribing from any newsletters or marketing, you can do this at any time in the Subscription Centre, which can be accessed by clicking the ‘Unsubscribe’ option at the bottom of our emails or by clicking 'Change contact preferences' in your profile (if you have a jamieoliver.com account). If you're having any issues unsubscribing please email [unsubscribe@jamieoliver.com](mailto:unsubscribe@jamieoliver.com). Please note it may take up to 14 days for your request to be fulfilled and you may continue to receive our emails during this period.

## Keeping your personal information secure

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We continually test our systems to make sure the level of security matches any risk and we run regular security tests by ISO 27001 certified partners.

Our website uses HTTPS which means that all data transferred from your web browser to our servers is encrypted. Our data servers are located in the United Kingdom. We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.  

For detailed information on how to protect your information and your computers and devices against fraud, identity theft, viruses and many other online risks, please visit [www.getsafeonline.org](http://www.getsafeonline.org/). Get Safe Online is supported by HM Government and leading businesses.

## How to complain

We hope that we can resolve any query or concern you raise about our use of your information.

The General Data Protection Regulation also gives you right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred. The supervisory authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner who may be contacted at <https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/> or telephone: 0303 123 1113.

## Changes to this privacy notice

This privacy notice was published on 23 May 2018 and last updated on 24 October 2019.

We may change this privacy notice from time to time, when we do we will we will post the changes on the Website. Where the changes are significant, we will inform all our registered users by email. Where required by law, will we obtain your consent to make these changes.

## How to contact us

Please contact us if you have any questions about this privacy notice or the information we hold about you.  
If you wish to contact us please:

  * use [this form](https://www.jamieoliver.com/contact/) (select 'Data Protection'), OR
  * write to us at Benwell House, 15-21 Benwell Road, London, England, N7 7BL

## Do you need extra help?

If you have difficulty reading the Table and/or would like this notice in another format (for example: audio, large print, braille) please contact us (see ‘How to contact us’ above).

## More about the information we collect and hold 

The information we collect | How we collect the information | Why we collect the information | How we use and may share the information  
---|---|---|---  
  
Information you provide during the “sign-up” process on jamieoliver.com:

  * e-mail address
  * first name and last name
  * gender
  * food preferences
  * family status (e.g children)
  * location

If you log-in with Social Media account credentials, we receive the information that you make available through the applicable Social Media or third party platform and that the applicable Social Media or third party platform has made available to us, in accordance with the privacy or other settings that are applicable to your Social Media or third party platform account.

| 

From you

From any Social Media or third party platform you log-in with

| 

Consent

Performance of a contract with you

For our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/ services, to develop them and grow our business)

| 

The minimum information we need to register you with a jamieoliver.com account is your name, email address and a password.

We use this information to identify you and provide you with the services you subscribe to, and where available, account-holder exclusive content.

We also allow you to answer voluntary questions during the registration process (for example your food preferences and family status). We use this information to personalise the services (including any marketing or newsletters you have opted-in to receive) we provide to you and to better understand who our audience is and what content they are interested in.  
  
Information you provide if you sign up to receive any of our marketing or newsletters (and if you subsequently update your marketing preferences):

  * your name
  * e-mail address and
  * marketing preferences

| 

From you

| 

Consent

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/ services)

| 

To promote Jamie Oliver products and services and deliver you the marketing communications you’re subscribed to.

To update your preferences and unsubscribe you if you request us to.

To manage our relationship with you, including to let you know about changes to our policies and terms.

In order to send our marketing or newsletters to you, we share this information with CRM providers who are located in the UK.  

Information you provide when you subscribe to one of our Exclusive Content Services (for example, “Five Day Veggie Challenge”):

  * account and authentication information
  * profile
  * contact information
  * payment confirmation (from our payment processors)
  * usage information

| 

From you

From our payment processor

| 

Performance of a contract with you

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)

| 

To process your subscription and deliver the service to you - including manage payments.

To collect information about how you use the Service, such as the type of content you view or engage with; the features you use; the actions you take; and the time, frequency and duration of your activities. We use this information to understand how our Services can be improved and made more relevant to our audience.  
  
Information you provide when you partake in one of our prize draws or competitions:

  * the information contained in your entry
  * your publicly available social media account details - when you partake via social media

| 

From you

| 

Performance of a contract with you (the terms applicable to the prize draw or competition)

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our business and inform our marketing strategy)

| 

To enable you to partake in a prize draw or competition and to communicate with you if you win.

We may use and re-publish personal information as part of our campaigns or to announce the winners on social media. Please see our Terms for Contributions and refer to the Terms and Conditions specific to the competition/prize draw.  
  
Information provided when you complete one of our surveys

| 

From Survey Monkey (a third party survey platform) - if you respond to one of our surveys via Survey Monkey

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)

| 

To collect feedback and suggestions from our customers and to better understand our audience.

Our surveys are powered by SurveyMonkey Inc., which is located in the USA. Accordingly, your information will be transferred to the USA. SurveyMonkey Inc. has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Its Privacy Policy is available [here](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/).  
  
Information you include in an inquiry or feedback

| 

From ZenDesk - If you contact us by using the “Contact” form on our Websites or by sending us an e-mail.

From a social media platform - if you contact us using Facebook Messenger, Instagram or Twitter.

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to respond to customers enquiries about our products/services)

| 

To allow you to contact us with and to respond to your enquiry and collect feedback.

May be shared with Jamie’s Italian Limited. Jamie’s Italian Limited is located in the UK.

May be shared with our third party licensees (and you may be contacted directly by them) our licensees are currently based in the EEA and Brazil.

ZenDesk Inc. powers our ‘Contact’ form. It is based in the USA and may transfer you personal information outside the EEA. When doing so, it relies on binding corporate rules (BCR) approved by the European data protection authorities or on other lawful measures, such as the EU standard contractual clauses or the Privacy Shield Framework - see its [Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.co.uk/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/).  
  
Information shared and made publicly accessible by you when you comment on recipes and content on our Websites, Services or Social Pages.

When you comment on recipes and content on our Websites, Services or Social Pages we do not receive any personal information other than that made available to us in your comment (including, if applicable, your social media handle and profile photo).

| 

From you

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to view and respond to customers comments and feedback about our products/services)

| 

To allow you to comment on recipes and content on our Websites.

We may use and re-publish personal information and content made publicly available within comments. Please see our [Terms for Contributions](https://www.jamieoliver.com/terms/).  
  
Information about purchase(s) you make on the [Jamie Oliver Shop](https://shop.jamieoliver.com/) (this does not include any payment or credit card details) 

| 

From the Hut.com Limited

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products, to keep our products relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  

| 

We use this information to define types of customers who purchase our products and create more products you will like.

The Jamie Oliver Shop is powered by the Hut.com Limited, which is located in the UK. Its privacy policy is available [here](https://shop.jamieoliver.com/privacy.list).  
  
If you fill in and submit our online form to be part an audience member or participate in one of our programmes, we collect the personal information you provide in the form.

Sometimes, we may ask you to provide us sensitive personal information (e.g. if you're sending in an application to be an audience member on a TV programme we may need to know whether you have any food allergies). When we do this we will provide further information about why we are collecting your information and how we will use it.

| 

From Typeform

| 

Consent

Performance of a contract with you (if you sign one of our contributor/release forms)

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recruit audience members and participants for our programmes)

| 

To select and invite audience members and participants for our TV programmes. We may also keep your information and contact you if similar opportunities to the one you expressed interest in arise in the future.

This form is powered by Typeform S.L., which is located in Spain. Typeform S.L. stores personal information in the EU and in the USA. Typerform’s Privacy Policy is available [here](https://admin.typeform.com/to/dwk6gt).  
  
If you visit our offices at Benwell House:

CCTV footage, guestbook entries, records of use of swipe cards and similar entry cards. 

| 

Physical and system security

| 

To comply with our legal obligations

For our legitimate interests (to manage and administer our business safely and effectively)

| 

We share this information with service providers who support our business, such as by providing CCTV technology and guest sign-in services.

We may also share this information if we are requested to provide CCTV images of you or any other personal information relating to you by police or any other government authority investigating suspected illegal activities.
